A Guide to the Rockefeller Family Audiovisual materials, General FA751
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Family Audiovisual materials, General
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller family
FA751
1 Film Reels Actual extent unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
When requesting to view films -- please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1902).
If the item does not have a designated AV number, please refer to the Title and the Film Number (which consists of a combination of Roman numerals and alphanumerics - example: III 14.1-6).
Conditions Governing Access
All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
The Audiovisual collection is an artificial collection created by the RAC in order to efficiently and effectively manage and present the moving images held among our archival holdings.
This material includes films and moving images in virtually every format available since the early 20th century including but not necessarily limited to: 16mm, 35mm, beta, Super 8, VHS and DVD.
Separated Materials
The majority of Audiovisual materials have been physically separated from a Rockefeller family archival collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In most cases, the specific details of the provenance are simply unknown.
Rockefeller family; Rockefeller family
- Rockefeller family films, General, 1
  Scope and Contents
  The Rockefeller family films represent a mix of private family footage, and published recordings from a multitude of sources. In the 1970s and 1980s, a reorganization effort duplicated and merged many of the original Rockefeller family films, so there is frequent overlap and repetition of some scenes, and many films contain a mix of private and public footage.
  See the Archival Services staff for more information about these films or guidance on finding a scene.
  The Rockefeller family (General) films contains moving images of multiple family members.
  Thereafter, are individual series focused on materials pertaining to, or otherwise related to, the activities of each prominent member of the Rockefeller family "Brothers Generation". Family members may be referred to by their full name, nickname, or abbreviation (such as NAR).
  - Construction of Rockefeller Center, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1386, Dvd AV 1603, Reel AV 1603)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
    Scope and Contents note
    Footage from 1931-1933 documenting the foundation and construction of Rockefeller Center, as directed by George Atwell
    File Plan
    III 14.9-4
    Architecture; Buildings; Atwell, George; Rockefeller Center
  - JDR IV Campaign in West Virginia, 1966 (Box 1, Dvd 110, Reel AV 110)
    Report on JDR IV campaign for W. Virginia seat in House of Delegates, reported by Paul Duke of NBC.
    III 14 F 2
    West Virginia; Political campaigns -- United States; West Virginia. Legislature. House of Delegates; Duke, Paul; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
  - Kykuit Photography Project, 1979
    Documenting the buildings and grounds at Kykuit, the Rockefeller home in Pocantico Hills, NY.
    IV 3B3.6a Fg 1 - IV 3B3.6a Fg 21
    Gardens -- Hudson River Valley (N.Y. and N.J.); Westchester County (N.Y.); Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); John D. Rockefeller House (Pocantico Hills, N.Y.); Architecture; Buildings
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #1 (Reel AV 874)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #2 (Reel AV 875)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #3 (Reel AV 876)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #4 (Reel AV 881)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #5 (Reel AV 882)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #6 (Reel AV 883)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #7 (Reel AV 884)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #8 (Reel AV 885)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #9 (Reel AV 886)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #10 (Reel AV 887)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #11 (Reel AV 888)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #12 (Reel AV 889)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #13 (Reel AV 890)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #14 (Reel AV 891)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #15 (Reel AV 892)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 1979 #16 (Reel AV 893)
    - Kykuit Photography Project: Cherry Blossoms Negative (Reel AV 894)
    - Kykuit Photography Project #10 (Reel AV 895)
    - Kykuit Photography Project #12 (Reel AV 896)
    - Kykuit #14 (Reel AV 897)
    - Kykuit Photography Project: Cherry Blossoms work print (Reel AV 898)
    - Kykuit Photography Project: Carriage House with Antiques and Modern Cars (Reel AV 899)
    - Kykuit #2: Main House Fascade (Reel AV 900)
    - Kykuit Photography Project #13 (Reel AV 901)
    - Kykuit Photography Project #8-1916 Simplex, Roof Views (Reel AV 902)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Japanese Garden Can #2 (Reel AV 903)
    - Kykuit Photography Project #13 (Reel AV 904)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Snow Scenes (Reel AV 905)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - January 1981 / Snow Scenes (Reel AV 906)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - August 31 #3 (Reel AV 926)
    - Kykuit Photography Project #4 (Reel AV 927)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 11/30/1979 #16, 30 November 1979 (Reel AV 928)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 10/22/80 #9, 22 October 1980 (Reel AV 929)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Carriage House Interiors (Reel AV 931)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 8/28/79 #1, 28 August 1979 (Reel AV 933)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 9/4/79 #5, 4 September 1979 (Reel AV 934)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 9/4/79 #6, 4 September 1979 (Reel AV 935)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 9/12/79 # 7, 12 September 1979 (Reel AV 936)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 9/12/79 # 8, 12 September 1979 (Reel AV 937)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 9/18/79 #9, 18 September 1979 (Reel AV 938)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 9/19/79 #11, 19 September 1979 (Reel AV 939)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 9/20/79 # 15, 20 September 1979 (Reel AV 940)
    - Kykuit Photography Project 11/19/80 Interior Playhouse #12, 19 November 1980 (Reel AV 941)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Japanese Garden Can #2 (Reel AV 942)
    - Kykuit Photography Project: Horse and Buggy up to Eagle Hill - Japanese Garden (Reel AV 943)
    - Kykuit Photography Project: Carriage House and Play House - Japanese Garden (Reel AV 944)
    - Kykuit Photography Project: Horse and Carriage, Kent House Exteriors (Reel AV 945)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Carriage House, Horses & Carriage, Kent House (Reel AV 946)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Simplex 1916 (Reel AV 947)
    - Kykuit Photography Project: 1916 Simplex Drive (Reel AV 948)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Fall Exteriors, 1980 (Reel AV 949)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Carriage House, Interiors (Reel AV 950)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Interior Carriage House (Reel AV 951)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - Playhouse #12 (Reel AV 952)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - 5/16/80 Horse and Buggy on Trail to Eagle Hill, 16 May 1980 (Reel AV 953)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - 5/22/80 Carriage House w/ Horses, 22 May 1980 (Reel AV 954)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - 5/23/80 Horse and Carriage Rides, 23 May 1980 (Reel AV 955)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - 5/28/80 Carriage House, Kent House, Main House, 28 May 1980 (Reel AV 956)
    - Kykuit Photography Project - 6/30/90 Grounds From Inside 1916 Simplex, 30 June 1990 (Reel AV 957)
  - March of Time: "Rockefeller Millions" (Reel AV 72, Box 1, Dvd AV 72)
    Episode from the newsreel series March of Time, a news compilation based on and sponsored by Time Magazine. This series covered national and international stories, using real footage and dramatized recreations, playing as 20 or 30 minute films in movie theaters from 1935 to 1951. HBO maintains copyright of this series. Includes NYC: scenes at Rockefeller Center: the family office, Room 5600; JDR JR working in office; construction; murals and artwork; Radio City and the Rockettes; the Rainbow Room; Rockefeller University; University of Chicago; Colonial Williamsburg.
    III 14 F 23
    Building; Buildings; Architecture; New York (N.Y.); Newsreels; Motion picture journalism; University of Chicago; Colonial Williamsburg (Williamsburg, Va.); Radio City Music Hall (New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller University; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller Center; Rockettes (Dance company); Rainbow Room (Restaurant)
  - The Rockefeller Family, 1917-1946 (Box 1, Dvd AV 3.1, Reel AV 1347, Box 2, Dvd AV 1347)
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Four copies of access DVD.
    Footage from several home movies shot in various locations, compiled in 1963: -10 W. 54th St, NYC: children of JDR, JR. playing inside; Laurance and Winthrop Rockefeller riding scooters inside; Laurance fixing scooter wheel (April 3, 1917) -Pocantico Hills, NY: Abby Rockefeller and sons playing with rabbits; David Rockefeller playing with dog, tricycle; five brothers riding bikes; Babs Rockefeller driving car; brothers riding horses with riding master Joe Plick; JDR JR driving in carriage; scenes of Kykuit; JDR SR golfing; JDR 3rd golfing; family at Union Church; JDR SR, JDR JR, Abby and sons on porch; panorama of the Playhouse (1919?) -JDR SR. in Ormond Beach, FL, reading letter on 60th anniversary of Standard Oil (Jan. 10, 1930) -Newsreel clip “John D. At 92 Leads Singing on Golf Links” (Fox Movietone News) (1931) -Newsreel clip “John D. Urges Faith!” (Paramount News) (1932) -Newsreel clip “Rockefeller Tees Up!” (Paramount News) (1932) -Newsreel clip “Rockefeller Dead at 97!” (Pathe News) (1937) with footage from Pocantico Hills, Riverside Church, Rockefeller Center (1937) -Newsreel clip “Restore Oldest American Castle” (Paramount News) about Philipsburg Manor restoration in Tarrytown NY -Newsreel clip “Scenes of Mr. and Mrs. Rockefeller JR. at Bassett Hall” (5/15/42) -Williamsburg, VA: JDR JR and Abby have tea at Bassett Hall; Abby knitting scarf for war effort; JDR JR reviewing blueprints with Kenneth Chorley and William Perry (May 1942) -Seal Harbor, ME: JDR JR with Abby and Winthrop Rockefeller in uniform in Eyrie Garden (1946)
    III 14.1-1
    Williamsburg (Va.); Tarrytown (N.Y.); Golf; Ormond Beach (Fla.); Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); West Fifty-fourth Street (New York, N.Y.); New York (N.Y.); Seal Harbor (Me.); Mauze, Abby Rockefeller; Union Church of Pocantico Hills (Pocantico Hills, N.Y.); Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Philipsburg Manor; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Riverside Church (New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller family; Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
  - Rockefeller Family (2) (Reel AV 1373)
    A compilation of home movies, similar to other compilation reels.
    III 14.1-19
    A compilation of home movies, similar to other compilation reels: -Ormond Beach, FL: JDR SR. reads letter on 60th anniversary of Standard Oil (Jan. 10, 1930) -NYC: scenes at Riverside Church and Rockefeller Center. -Pocantico Hills, NY: Abby and sons; David Rockefeller playing with dog, tricycle; five brothers riding bikes; Babs Rockefeller driving car (1919?) -newsreel “Senator Bulkley of Ohio Supports Rockefeller’s View”
    Home movies; Amateur films; Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); New York (N.Y.); Ormond Beach (Fla.); Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Bulkley, Robert Johns, Robert Johns; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller family; Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Mauze, Abby Rockefeller; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller Center; Riverside Church (New York, N.Y.)
  - Rockefeller Family (4) (Box 2, Dvd AV 1356, Reel AV 1356, Dvd AV 1390)
    III 14.1-8
    -Pocantico Hills: family at Union Church; family at Playhouse; JDR SR, JDR JR, Abby and sons on porch (1919?) -Florida: JDR SR with friends; golfing; driving a wagon; at Ormond Beach Baptists Church; visit with Will Rogers; at costumed “chariot race”
    Golf; Chariot racing; Florida; Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); John D. Rockefeller House (Pocantico Hills, N.Y.); Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller family; Union Church of Pocantico Hills (Pocantico Hills, N.Y.); Rogers, Will
  - Rockefeller Family (6) (Reel AV 1390, Box 2, Dvd AV 1390)
    III 14.1-11
    - JDR SR with his granddaughter Mathilde McCormick Oser, her husband Max Oser, and their children Anita and Peter: -group scenes at Lakewood NJ -golfing with group -with JDR JR and Abby
    Golf; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller family; Oser, Mathilde McCormick; Oser, Max; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich
  - Rockefeller Family (8) (Reel AV 1364, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.22, Dvd AV 822)
    III 14.1-16
    -Woodstock VT: Laurance Rockefeller’s marriage to Mary French (1934) -Bala PA: Nelson Rockefeller’s marriage to Mary T. Clark (1930) -compilation of newsreels “JDR SR Dead at 97”: golfing; in Ormond Beach FL; attending Union Church; at Rockefeller Center; JDR JR and sons receiving the casket at Tarrytown train station, Pocantico Hills home (1937)
    Ormond Beach (Fla.); Tarrytown (N.Y.); Newsreels; Golf; Wedding; Woodstock (Vt.); Marriage service; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller Center; Union Church of Pocantico Hills (Pocantico Hills, N.Y.); Rockefeller, Mary (Mary Todhunter Clark); Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller, Mary French; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Rockefeller family
  - Rockefeller Family (9) (Reel AV 1353)
    III 14.4-7
    -NYC newsreel “Rockefeller Center Seen as Symbol of World Unity”; British Empire Building cornerstone -Bar Harbor, ME: JDR 3rd at dedication of Arcadia National Parks scenic highway -NYC: JDR 3rd marriage to Blanchette Hooker (November 11, 1932) -Pocantico Hills, NY: JDR SR reads speech “Urges Faith” to nation on his 93rd birthday
    Marriage service; Wedding; Bar Harbor (Me.); New York (N.Y.); Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Birthdays; Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller Center; Rockefeller, John D.
  - Rockefeller Family (10) (Reel AV 1367)
    III 14.2-12
    -Versailles, France newsreel “JDR JR Honored by France” for restoration assistance -NYC: JDR 3rd marriage to Blanchette Hooker (November 11, 1932), honeymoon to Bermuda & return to NYC -NAR speech “Share the Work” supporting 40-hour, 5-day work week -includes footage from Pathe News, Fox News, and Paramount News
    Newsreels; Versailles (France); Wedding; Honeymoons; New York (N.Y.); Marriage service; Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, John D.; Fox News; Pathe News
  - Rockefeller Family (11) (Box 2, Dvd AV 1366, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.24, Reel AV 1366)
    III 14.2-15
    -compilation of newsreels from the 1930’s: -newsreel clips: “JDR JR Drives Last Rivet in Rockefeller Center”; “Rockefeller in Peace Plan”; “Rockefeller’s Grandson Nelson Rockefeller Makes Movie Debut”
    Awards; Architecture; Building; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller Center; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller family
  - Rockefeller Family (12) (Box 2, Dvd AV 1351, Reel AV 1351)
    -David Rockefeller marriage to Margaret McGrath (1944) -JDR 3rd speech on Radio City, NY World’s Fair -Winthrop Rockefeller army induction -JDR 3rd at celebration of Virginia Legislation -Nelson Rockefeller presents awards to Rockefeller Center construction workers -newsreel “Rockefeller Heir Initiated by Saints and Sinners” circus scenes with Winthrop Rockefeller -Colonial Williamsburg, VA: restoration of historic tavern
    Newsreels; Awards; Buildings -- Repair and reconstruction; Circus; Virginia. General Assembly; Rockefeller family; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller Center; New York World's Fair (1939-1940: New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, Peggy; Radio City Music Hall (New York, N.Y.)
  - Rockefeller Family (13) (Reel AV 1372)
    III 14.2-24
    -1960 newsreel from Fox Movietone News: Nelson Rockefeller with Dwight D. Eisenhower at Labor Day Parade in NYC; memorial service for JDR Jr.; Steven Rockefeller’s wedding; Happy Rockefeller with Steven and Anne-Marie
    New York (N.Y.); Newsreels; Wedding; Marriage service; Memorial service; Parades; Rockefeller family; Fox Movietone News; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight D.); Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, Steven C.; Rockefeller, Margaretta Fitler
  - Rockefeller Family Home Movies, 1920s (Box 1, Dvd AV 56, Reel AV 56)
    III 14 F 5
    -Pocantico Hills, NY: brothers & friends swimming in lake, pool, pillow fights on the lawn, riding in cars; David Rockefeller with Abby and JDR SR; JDR SR with JDR JR, JDR 3rd on porch -Posing for Koshiba portraits: JDR SR, JDR JR, Abby, David Milton, Babs and baby Mitzi, Babs with baby Mitzi; Winthrop Rockefeller; Abby with granddaughter Mitzi
    Swimming; Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Rockefeller family; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, John D.; Mauze, Abby Rockefeller
  - Rockefeller Newsreel Compilation (Reel AV 1916)
    Reprint of a Paramount News compilation of clips about the Rockefeller Family, construction at Rockefeller Center, etc.
    Buildings; Building; Newsreels; Rockefeller Center; Rockefeller family
  - The Rockefellers, 1973 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1324, Reel AV 1324)
    A history of the Family as presented by CBS News. Walter Cronkite interviews Abby Mauze, JDR 3rd, Nelson, Laurance, and David Rockefeller.
    Five copies of access DVD.
    III 14 F 63
    Filmed interviews; Family history; CBS News; Rockefeller family; Mauze, Abby Rockefeller; Cronkite, Walter; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
  - Scenes of Kykuit (Reel AV 1411, Reel AV 1412, Reel AV 1413, Reel AV 1414)
    From an undated commercial shoot, views of the house and gardens at the Pocantico Hills estate (no family members shown).
    Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Gardens; John D. Rockefeller House (Pocantico Hills, N.Y.)
- Rockefeller family audio materials, General